下面是一个关于有理数的抽象数据类型的例子。
Here's an example of an abstract data type for rational numbers.
让我们仔细看看它的rep不变量及其抽象
Let's look closely at its rep invariant and its abstraction
功能。
function.
下面是抽象函数的图片
Here's a picture of the abstraction function
以及此代码的rep不变量。
and the rep invariant for this code.
rep不变量要求分子和分母
The rep invariant requires that the numerator and denominator
成对的是简化的形式，最低限度的。
pairs be in reduced form, lowest terms.
所以像2逗号4，18逗号12这样的对
So pairs like 2 comma 4, 18 comma 12
应该画成国际扶轮以外的。
should be drawn as outside of the RI.
现在，这是完全合理的设计
Now, it'd be perfectly reasonable to design
同一ADT的另一个实现
another implementation of the same ADT
用一个更宽容的RI。
with a more permissive RI.
有了这样的变化
With such a change, some of the operations
可能会变得更昂贵，
might become more expensive to perform,
但其他的可能会更便宜。
but other ones might become cheaper.
现在，rep不变量不仅仅是一个简洁的数学概念。
Now, the rep invariant isn't just a neat mathematical idea.
如果您的实现在运行时声明其rep不变量，
If your implementation asserts its rep invariant at run time,
那么你可以很快失败。
then you can fail fast.
你可以早点抓到虫子。
You can catch bugs earlier.
这里有一个方法可以用来[？拉特南？]测试它的rep不变量。
Here's a method for [? ratnam ?] that tests its rep invariant.
我们叫它支票代表。
We'll call it check rep.
它返回void，因为它将执行断言。
It returns void because it's going to be doing assertions.
注意，除非你
Note that this does nothing unless you
打开断言检查。
turn on assertion checking.
它所做的是断言发现的每一个条件
And what it does is asserts each of the conditions found
在我们的代表不变量。
in our rep invariant.
你当然应该打电话给支票代表
You should certainly call check rep
在每个操作结束时断言rep不变量
to assert the rep invariant at the end of every operation that
创造或变异代表——换句话说，创造者，
creates or mutates the rep-- in other words, creators,
生产者和变异者。
producers, and mutators.
所以如果你回头看看那个？拉特南？]上面的代码，
So if you look back at the [? ratnam ?] code above,
你会看到它在每一个结束时调用check rep
you will see that it calls check rep at the end of each
建造者的。
of the constructors.
他们都是创造者。
Those are both creators.
观察者方法通常不需要调用check rep，
Observer methods don't normally need to call check rep,
但无论如何，这样做是很好的防守练习。
but its good defensive practice to do so anyway.
为什么？
Why?
嗯，每种方法都有召回检查代表，包括
Well, with recall check rep in every method including
观察者，这意味着你会
observers, that means you'd be more
可能会捕捉到代表不变的违反
likely to catch rep invariant violations that
是由于暴露在rep中引起的。
are caused by rep exposure.
为什么支票代表是私人的？
Now, why is check rep private?
谁负责检查和执行
Who should be responsible for checking and enforcing
代表不变量？
a rep invariant?
客户还是实现本身？
The clients or the implementation itself?
现在，回想一下我们的说明书
Now, recall from our specs reading
空值非常麻烦和不安全
that null values are troublesome and unsafe, so much
所以我们试图将它们从我们的编程中完全删除。
so that we try to remove them from our programming entirely.
在6005年，先决条件和后决条件
And in 6005 the preconditions and postconditions
我们的方法隐式地要求数组中的对象
of our methods implicitly require that objects in arrays
非空。
be non-null.
我们不必这么说。
We don't have to say that.
我们只是不想要空的。
We just don't want null.
所以我们应该延长禁令
So we should extend that prohibition
给抽象数据类型的代表。
to the reps of abstract data types.
默认情况下，在6005中，rep不变量隐式地
By default, in 6005, the rep invariant implicitly
对于每个引用，includes x不等于null，
includes x is not equal to null for every reference,
对象引用或数组引用，代表中的x。
object reference or array reference, x in the rep.
所以如果你的rep是字符串s，那么它的rep不变
So if your rep is string s, then its rep invariant automatically
includes s不等于空。
includes s is not equal to null.
您不需要在rep不变注释中声明它。
You don't need to state it in a rep invariant comment.
但是到了在支票中实现rep不变量的时候
But when it's time to implement that rep invariant in a check
rep方法，您仍然应该实现
rep method, you should still implement the s is not
等于空检查。
equal to null check.
当s为空时，确保您的支票代表正确地失败。
Make sure that your check rep correctly fails when s is null.
这种检查常常是从Java免费获得的
So often that check comes for free from Java
因为检查你的代表不变量的其他部分
because checking other parts of your rep invariant
如果s为空，将引发异常。
will throw an exception if s is null.
例如，如果您的支票代表
For example, if your check rep has
因为你在检查s的长度，
to look like this because you're checking the length of s,
那么你不需要断言
then you don't need to assert s is not
等于空，因为对s.length的调用
equal to null because the call to s.length
在空引用上同样有效地失败。
will fail just as effectively on a null reference.
但是如果s没有被rep不变量检查，
But if s is not otherwise checked by the rep invariant,
则断言s不显式等于null。
then assert s is not equal to null explicitly.